In this video, I am going to discuss 10 such large-cap and mid-cap
which provide high returns with low risk
I have used the concept of alpha and beta to consider these stocks
In our coming video, we will discuss a bit more about this concept
Now let's start with our discussion on growth stocks
Our 1st stock idea is a retail consumption story
which has given an average return of 54% CAGR to its investors in the past 3 years
Its profits have increased by an average of 28% CAGR
This stock is Dmart
Now let me introduce you to the concept of alpha and beta
Alpha indicates how much the stock has performed better than its index, here ie. Nifty
Nifty has given a 17% CAGR return on average in the past 3 years
and Dmart has given a return of 54% CAGR in last 3 years
This extra outperformance of 37%
is called alpha
Beta shows how volatile the stock is as compared to the Nifty
If the value of beta is less than 1
it shows that this stock is less volatile than Nifty
In case of Dmart, its Beta is around 0.42
and because of its high alpha and low beta is is a high return, low-risk story
Currently, Dmart is trading at a PE multiple of more than 200
Which I personally think is expensive
So here any correction can provide a good opportunity for longterm
SIP as well is a good strategy to minimize your risk
So if you have dmart in your portfolio then do like this video
2nd stock idea is an IT giant with 3lakh crore of market cap
This stock has given on average a return of 29% CAGR
If I compare it with Nifty's 17% CAGR
we get an outperformance of 32%
Its beta is around 0.84
which shows that its risk prospects are also good
This stock is HCL technologies
However, it hasn't given great results as compared to its industry
and so it is at a PE OF 27
If I compare it with TCS and Infosys
they are trading at a PE of 35 and 36
The first thing that makes HCL attractive is its valuations
also, it has a strong deal pipeline
In the previous HCL has made 14 new deals
of 2200 million dollar+
this deal is promising for its coming quarters
We are also going to discuss an IT as well as AI-driven company
Our next stock idea is from the infrastructure sector
and its market cap is around 2lakh crore
It is  a market leader and has its presence in North, east, west
and south
They have 26% of the market share in cement production
and I am talking about Ultratech cement
It has given a return of 24% CAGR as compared to 17% of Nifty
So here its alpha is around 7%
15% of ROCE
operating profit margins of 25%
and a debt to equity of 0.33
11% of free cashflow generation on invested capital
shows how financially strong the company is
Our next stock is an FMCG Giant
and a market leader in its category
having 66% pf infant food market share
63% of chocolate market share
70% market share on condensed milk
and 69% of market share in noodles category
I am talking about Nestle India
It has given a return of average of 23% CAGR to its investors
It is not that great when we look at 17% of Nifty
But FMCG is traditionally a defensive sector
which is least affected by market crashes
Its bets=a is around 0.24
This clearly shows that it's quite less volatile as compared to Nifty
It has been a consistent compounder for since last 10 yrs
It has more than 100% of return ratios
25% of operating profit margin
It generates 93% of free cash flow on its invested capital
which clearly shows that their business is phenomenal
Insurance is an underpenetrated industry in India
Only 1% of GDP goes to the payment of premiums
In developed economy it is around 2%
In a country like US, it is around 9%
In the years to come the increasing financial awareness
rising disposable income
and rising healthcare expenditure
will give a boost to the insurance sector
This stock that I am talking about is ICICI Lombard
It has given on an average 23% CAGR return in last 3 yrs
as compared to 17% of Nifty
Its beta is around 0.64
and its profits in last 3 yrs have increased by 36% CAGR
However, this stock was under pressure due to covid
It provides an exciting opportunity for longterm
Last year due to covid there has been a major change in the pharma and API industry
This stock operates in the API segment
It provides main ingredients to the pharma companies
along with this they also have a custom synthesis verticle
This company is not in the space of formulations
and that is why it does not compete with its pharma clients and costumers
In last 3 yrs it has given a return of 46% CAGR
This is a significant outperformance as compared to 17% of Nifty
Its beta is around 0.27
which shows a great stability
This company is Divis Labs
Operating profit margin of more than 40%
A debt-free business and more than 30% of ROCE
These are phenomenal numbers
Right now API is facing challenges in terms of raw material
and in such a challenging environment, it has shown a QoQ growth
It is important to note that because of strong performance it is trading at premium valuations
No doubt that there are valuation concerns
but any correction or SIP provides an exciting opportunity for longterm
Our next stock idea is a midcap IT company
which is constantly increasing its market cap
In the last 10 years, it has constantly shown double-digit sales and profit growth
In last 11 years, int profit has increased from 200crs to 1200crs
In the past 3 years, it has given 81% CAGR return
In the same period, Nifty midcap 100 has given a return of 22% CAGR
So this has an alpha of 59%
its beta is around 0.89
This company is Mindtree
However this stock is also trading at premium valuations
But its strong fundamentals indicate
a good opportunity in case of any correction or SIP
Now let's talk about the future themes
like 5G, AI, Artificial intelligence
So any investor can either invest in any of these themes individually
or invest in such a stock that works in all of these themes
We are going to talk about such a stock which is Larsen and Toubro technologies
This stock has given on an average 52% of CAGR return
This is a significant outperformance as compared to 22% of Nifty midcap 100
Its beta is also around 0.91
Because of this its prospects become exciting
LTTS is currently at a PE of 68
So this might be expensive for us standalone
But if compare it to Tata elexi
which is at a PE of 90
and Happiest Minds which is at a PE of 118
Here definitely there is a relative comfort
The algorithm of Youtube also works on AI
So if your portfolio has any AI stock then do press that like button
which will indicate the algorithm of youtube
The auto sector has been a serious underperformer for a few years
But I am going to discuss a stock that has given a return of 35% CAGR in last 3 yrs
It has an alpha of 10% when compared to 22% of Nifty midcap 100
its beta is around 0.94
and I am talking about Balkrishna Industries
it is into the business of off-highway tires
and they have a revenue of 78% from exports
It has more than 20% of return ratios
OPM of 29%
Debt to equity of 0.24
48% of profit growth in last 12 months
This shows how this company is financially well-off
Previous its total sales volume was around 2.27 lakhs mt
This time it is around 2.87 lakh mt
So this is quite a bullish indicator
and because of its strong fundamentals you can definitely explore this stock
Disclaimer: This video is not a recommendation
and it is only for educational purpose
so please consult your financial advisor before any investment decisions
Our last company has a 40k cr marketcap
in agrochemical sector
Their significant business comes from exports
Recently agrochemical sector has been disrupted due to supply chains
also due to erratic monsoon conditions, it is under pressure
But in such a challenging time as well it has given a YoY revenue growth of 17%
and 615 of YoY PAD growth
It has given a return of average of 52% CAGR to its investors in last 3 yrs
Their alpha is around 30% as compared to 22% of Nifty midcap 100
their beta is also around 0.86
which indicates less volatility
This company going ahead is targeting growth via acquisitions as well
This stock is PI industries
It is targeting API pharma segment in the future
where they can provide custom synthesis
So its overall indicators are quite positive
It will be interesting to watch out how it pans out its pharma expansion
It might not be an easy pull out for them
But if it is able to execute it successfully
then it can be a potential game-changer
Just like this company we have covered another
Midcap agro company which is Sumitomo chemical
Its fundaments are also quite strong
You will definitely like that video as well!